#### James Brink

Sunnyvale, CA (480) 231-4300

brink.james@gmail.com

With over ten years of professional experience in application development, system administration, and networking, I am looking for a position that offers me the greatest challenges and opportunities to grow. My passion for learning is second only to that of solving complex problems with elegant solutions.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Operating Systems: Linux, Solaris, FreeBSD, Windows Server

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Oracle Networking: Cisco IOS, Load Balancers, Firewalls Languages: Ruby, Java, Python, JavaScript, SQL

Version Control: Git, CVS, MKS Source

Cloud & Virtualization: Docker, OpenStack, AWS

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Operations Engineer (2015 - Present), Yahoo, Sunnyvale, CA Currently working on the Small Business Services team.

### Systems Administrator II (2008 - 2015), Edward Jones, Tempe, AZ

Initially hired to monitor and maintain infrastructure for a range of enterprise applications. Responsibilities included application deployment, incident triage, and troubleshooting Linux and Windows environments. Promoted to System Administrator II after demonstrating an aptitude for tackling complicated infrastructure problems from availability to disaster recovery.

- Selected as department Datacenter Continuity Coordinator.
- Built and maintained multiple utilities within our department to assist in things from daily tasks to incident troubleshooting. These included both web and desktop applications in addition to command line utilities.
- Created a Java application that allows associates to document, lookup, and quickly identify support teams and potential business impact for any application running in production.
- Developed tools that enabled associates to automate the collection data and generation of reports.

# Software Engineer (2011 - 2012), Media Solutions Corp, Phoenix, AZ

Contracted to lead an effort to bring a project that was 4 months behind, up to date and in production. Utilizing Ruby on Rails, was able to start from scratch and rapidly develop and deploy the necessary features to bring the product into production within 2 weeks. Over the following year I mentored and trained another Ruby developer. During this year we focused on bringing the application up to the changing requirements, utilizing Agile methodologies and short iterative releases.

- Brought a project that was 4 months behind to production within 2 weeks.
- Responsible for hiring and training 2 additional engineers.
- Worked closely with product manager to resolve any outstanding issues and address new
  - features quickly.
- Leveraged agile methodologies for all additional application features.
- Managed the Rackspace cloud infrastructure including maintenance, backups, and security updates.

## Network Engineer/Systems Integrator (2004 - 2008), Accram, Phoenix, AZ

While at Accram, my time was split between managing internal infrastructure, running the company's small ISP, as well as managing customers networks and servers. My daily duties varied dramatically from one day to another, as we were always taking on new customers with new challenges. Spent a lot of time on projects, generally working as a lead. Selected to manage and lead customer technical onboarding and integrations. Worked directly with sales teams to identify and pursue new customers and deliver solutions specific to their needs.

- Planned and led infrastructure initiatives that included networking, server deployment, and cabling.
- Leveraged open source tools to engineer and implement a monitoring infrastructure for internal and external networks.
- Managed internal web applications, e-mail servers, and DNS.
- Responsible for ensuring application redundancy and tested failover.

## **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA) - 2007.

Diploma in Satellite Communications from the Department of the Army - 2001.

Diploma in Network Switching Systems from General Dynamics - 2001.

Diploma in Computer Technology from the Arizona Institute of Business Technology - 2000.

CompTIA A+ from Stellar International Institute - 2000.